Guide to the Arthur H. Landis Oral History Collection ALBA.AUDIO.066
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Arthur H. Landis Oral History Collection
1963-1965
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Landis, Arthur H., 1917-1986
ALBA.AUDIO.066
6 Linear Feet
89 audiocassette
71 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel
Arthur H. Landis (1917-1986) went to Spain in 1937 as a volunteer with the 15th International Brigade and fought with the MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion. In 1967, Landis wrote The Abraham Lincoln Brigade, a general history of American volunteers in the Spanish Civil War, and later published Spain! The Unfinished Revolution, about the political complexities of the war. The Landis collection of audiotapes consists primarily of interviews with American Spanish Civil War veterans conducted in the 1960s as part of his research for The Abraham Lincoln Brigade. A few miscellaneous tapes recorded for other purposes are also included.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Each tape has been assigned a unique item number (i.e., ALBA A 48-11), and the collection is arranged in item number order. In general, the tapes are arranged alphabetically by the first name mentioned in the caption.
Entries in the reel-to-reel item lists indicate whether there is a CD reference copy and/or audiocassette copies. The reference CDs are numbered to correspond with the reel-to-reel numbers (followed by an "R") and are stored separately. Cassette copies are numbered ALBA A 66-72 through ALBA A 66-160 and are arranged numerically and stored separately.
The files are organized in 2 series:
Missing Title
I, Reel-to-Reel Tapes, Book Project, 1963-1965.
II, Miscellaneous Reel-to-Reel Tapes, 1945-1970.
Historical/Biographical Note
Arthur H. Landis (1917-1986) went to Spain in 1937 to join the 15th International Brigade; he served with the MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, as an American volunteer in what became a predominantly Canadian unit. In 1967, Landis wrote The Abraham Lincoln Brigade, a general history of American volunteers in the Spanish Civil War, and later published Spain! The Unfinished Revolution, about the political complexities of the war.
The Arthur H. Landis Oral History Collection is comprised primarily of approximately 100 hours of audio-taped recordings of American veterans of the Spanish Civil War. The original 1/4" tapes were created between 1963 and 1965 as part of the research for Landis's The Abraham Lincoln Brigade. Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) associates around the country, alone and in small groups, recorded their memories of battles and day-to-day activities in which they had participated.
The idea of audio-taping veterans first occurred to Landis in April of 1963, and by August 1964 the project was gathering steam. On August 10th Landis sent a letter to VALB associate Donald Thayer in San Francisco detailing the information that he was seeking from SCW veterans. Thayer excerpted Landis's letter in a general mailing to VALB members, requesting that they make their own audiotapes, in which they were to supply detailed information about their battalions, units, firepower, orders received, positions occupied, nature of attacks, terrain conditions, day-to-day positions, casualties and prisoners, wins and losses, "human-interest vignettes," promotions or substitutions, and related information. Landis emphasized that he still badly needed information on Aragon, Teruel, the Retreats, and the Ebro. A decade after the research was completed, Landis recalled that the tapes contained the "detailed examination of American brigade and battalion involvement in a particular battle or series of battles in a particular campaign, and/or the structure, personnel and participation in action of a unit such as transport, artillery, the American Medical Bureau, etc." At least 20 of the tapings were not personally attended by Landis, but were produced according to his explicit instructions. Veterans Steve Nelson and Donald Thayer conducted a handful of the interviews. After Landis completed a draft of the book, veterans in VALB's New York office met and recorded their suggestions for changes (tapes ALBA A 66-2 and ALBA A 66-36).
Landis's research project stimulated intense interest among VALB members. Donald Thayer reported that when he played a tape made for Landis by a veteran for a group of VALB members, it stirred in the vets "all of the memories of the Brigade years."
Responding to a comment in 1977 by veteran Randall "Pete" Smith that Landis had downplayed the involvement of a fellow SCW veteran in his book, Landis recounted in a detailed letter the way in which veterans had been notified about the project, charging the New York VALB office with neglecting to invite the participation of a number of vets.
In the late sixties, Landis tried to interest the VALB leadership in funding a project to preserve the audiotapes, and later proposed a project that went beyond preservation. He explained his reasons for wanting to embark on this project in a 1974 letter to Brandeis University Special Collections Librarian Victor Berch, arguing that "new tapes [should] be made--and quickly, before the rest of us die off." Landis further proposed to "edit and re-tape" the tapes he had of vets who had already died. This project does not appear to have been carried out. But in the 1980s the reel-to-reel tapes were copied to audiocassettes.
For further biographical information on Arthur Landis, and for more information on the audiotape project see, Arthur H. Landis Papers, ALBA #66.
Provenance
The Arthur H. Landis Oral History Collection was donated to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives by Arthur H. Landis in the early 1980s. The collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University. The audiotapes in the Arthur H. Landis Collection were separated from the Arthur H. Landis Papers at the time of processing.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access CDs for audiovisual materials in the collection are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only.
Access to some audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library.
Arthur H. Landis Papers (ALBA 66)
Arthur H. Landis Photograph Collection (ALBA Photo 66)
Scope and Content Note
For the audiotape project Landis provided veterans with a demo tape (ALBA A 66-038) that "gave the outline structure of the book and a detailed explanation of his desire to give adequate attention to all phases of the war which Americans participated in, from ambulance drivers to the commando zealots." Further, Landis stressed: "material for taping [should] be put in chronological order to avoid a time-consuming play-back," that veterans "make notes before making the tape," and "tape at a speed of 3-1/4." Members were told that they could use their own tape recorders, or that VALB would loan out both a recorder and tapes.
The tapes were not professionally recorded, nor were the sessions conducted as conventional oral histories. Consequently, the sound quality varies from tape to tape, and veterans at times do not identify themselves or provide many autobiographical details. The focus is on their day-by-day participation in the Spanuish Civil War.
Series I: Reel-to-Reel Tapes. Book Project, 1963-1965, contains individual and group interviews conducted in the course of research for Arthur Landis's book, The Abraham Lincoln Brigade, and one demo tape produced by Landis.
Series II: Miscellaneous Reel-to-Reel Tapes, 1945-1970, consists mostly of interviews with Spanish Civil War veterans, some commenting on Landis's published work, and music tapes, several of which feature singer (and veteran) Bart Van der Schelling singing songs of the Spanish Civil War. Van der Schelling is pictured with Paul Robeson and Arthur Landis, among others, in a photograph in the Arthur H. Landis Photo Collection.
The availability of CD reference copies and audiocassettes copies in indicated in the entries for individual items. Reel-to-reel tapes labeled "not transferable" in the descriptions were damaged or posed other serious problems that prevented transferring them to CD.
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Women.; Murcia (Spain); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Personal narratives.; Albacete (Spain); Valencia (Spain); Audiocassettes.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Hospitals.; Madrid (Spain); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Schulman, Rebecca (Durem); Secundy, Louis; Quinones, Gabriel Jack; Fishman, Mosess (Moe), 1916-2007; Schelling, Bart van der, 1892-1970; Pappas, Nick; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Munday, Arthur; Nelson, Steve, 1903-1993; Wolff, Milton.; Geiser, Carl; Fisher, Harry, 1911-2003; Nusser, Charles; Goff, Irving; Goddard, Howard, 1911-1997; Chaikin, George, 1908-1992; Warren, Alvin; Brown, Archie, 1911-1990.; Smith, Randall, 1917-1989; Goldstein, Benjamin, 1910-1985; Cane, Lawrence, 1912-1976; Smith, Harold; Osheroff, Abe; Zlotnick, Louis; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. Historical Commission; Harriman, Manny; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. Archives; Wellman, Wilbur Ed; Brandt, Joseph, 1909-1997; Wheeler, William Gilmore; Parker, Max, 1912-1983.; Klein, Herman (Gabby); Thayer, Donald; Houlihan, Sara; Groden, Daniel Samuel; Haber, Cohn; Sennett, William, 1914-; Tivin, Isidore; Van Clute, Walton.; Shaker, Kenneth R.; Stuart, Yale; Bevensee, Court; Blair, John; Thompson, Robert George, 1915-1966; MacLeod, Donald; Davidow, Ruth; Taft, Anne, 1912-1990; Landis, Arthur H., 1917-1986; Gittelson, Lester; Foucek, George; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Brigada Internacional, XV; Berch, Victor A.; Klonsky, Robert; Barsky, Edward K., 1895-1975; Hutchins, Evelyn, 1910-1982; Kusman, Felix, 1909-1983; Love, Vaughn; Levine, Sidney R.; McNeil, Allan; Eider, Louis; Hyman, Frank Chesler; Colow, Maury; Keir, Duncan, Jr.; Kaufman, Rubin; Keller, Ruth; Keller, Fred Paul
- Series I: Reel-to-Reel Tapes, 1962-1965.
  - Barsky, Edward; Duncan Keir, Jr., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_1, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_72, 66_73, 66_74, Box 3, Cd 66_1)
  - Bevensee, Court; and Moe Fishman. Second and Last Session on Brunete and Bevensee's comments on the draft of Landis' book., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_2, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_75, Box 3, Cd 66_2)
  - Blair, John; and [Cohn Haber?] Discussing the structure of the MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion and joining the 15th Brigade outside of Quinto., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_3, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_76, 66_77, 66_78, 66_79, Box 3, Cd 66_3)
  - Brandt, Joe. [Not transferable], undated (Box 1, Reel 66_4, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_80, 66_81, 66_82, 66_83)
  - Brown, Archie; George Foucek; Sidney Levine; and Donald Thayer. On re-crossing of the Ebro., Oct 31, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 66_5, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_84, Box 3, Cd 66_5)
  - Brown, Archie; George Foucek; Sidney Levine; and Donald Thayer. Continuing the discussion of Gandesa, while Foucek describes activities leading up to Hill 666., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_6, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_85, Box 3, Cd 66_6)
  - Cane, Lawrence (Larry); and Carl Geiser., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_7, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_86, Box 3, Cd 66_7)
  - Cane, Lawrence (Larry); and Art Landis., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_8, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_87, Box 3, Cd 66_8)
  - Chaiken, George; and Felix Kusman. Kusman discusses the action at Quinto and Belchite, and what the company did on the first, second and third day at Quinto., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_9, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_88, Box 3, Cd 66_9)
  - Chesler, Frank; and Max Robert Klonsky. Klonsky describes late 1936 when he agreed to go to Spain and how he went to the Army & Navy store in lower Manhattan to get equipment. [Not transferable], undated (Box 1, Reel 66_10, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_91, 66_92)
  - Chesler, Frank; and Robert Thompson. Discussing Fuentes del Ebro on the Aragon Front where [?] commanded the MacKenzie-Papineau Canadian Battalion., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_11, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_89, 66_90, 66_93)
  - Van Clute, Wilton; Nick (Mike) Pappas; and Kenneth R. Shaker., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_12, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_94, 66_95, 66_96, 66_97, Box 3, Cd 66_12)
  - [Colow, Maury?]; and Moe Fishman, undated (Box 1, Reel 66_13, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_75, Box 3, Cd 66_13)
  - Colow, Maury; Milton Wolff., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_14, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_98, 66_99, Box 3, Cd 66_14)
  - Davidow, Ruth; George Foucek; Donald MacLeod; and Wilbur Ed Wellman., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_15, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_79, 66_101, Box 3, Cd 66_15)
  - Durem, Rebecca (Schulman). Landis: "It was my understanding that the State Department...threw a little difficulty in your way before the first group [of nurses] got its passports...", undated (Box 1, Reel 66_16, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_146, 66_147, Box 4, Cd 66_16)
  - Eider, Louis., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_17, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_102, 66_103, Box 4, Cd 66_17)
  - Fishman, Moe; and Harold Smith. "Bryce Coleman, whose body I saw outside of Villanueva de Canada...", Jun 1, 1964 (Box 1, Reel 66_18, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_151, Box 4, Cd 66_18)
  - Fisher, Harry; Steve Nelson; Charles Nusser; and Harold Smith. On Brunete., Apr 1964 (Box 1, Reel 66_19, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_123, 66_131, 66_141, Box 4, Cd 66_19)
  - Foucek, George; Sara Houlihan; Ruth Keller; Donald MacLeod; Donald Thayer; Wilbur Ed Wellman. After the Belchite Action., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_20, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_108, Box 4, Cd 66_20)
  - Foucek, George; Sidney Levine; Donald MacLeod; and Steve Nelson. Added Material on the Ebro; Terrain at the Battle of Aragon., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_21, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_109, Box 4, Cd 66_21, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_104)
  - Foucek, George; Sidney Levine; Donald MacLeod; and Donald Thayer. Teruel., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_22, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_105, 66_106, 66_107, Box 4, Cd 66_22)
  - Goddard, Howard Owen; Evelyn Hutchins; and Gabriel Jack Quinones, undated
    - Audio reel, cuid43717 (Box 1, Reel 66_23)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Duration: 149 minutes; Preservation note: Digitally stretched
    - Audiocassette (Box 6, Audiocassette 66_81)
    - Audiocassette (Box 7, Audiocassette 66_112)
    - Audiocassette (Box 7, Audiocassette 66_113)
  - Goddard, Howard Owen; Evelyn Hutchins; and Gabriel Jack Quinones, undated
    - Audio reel, cuid43718 (Box 1, Reel 66_24)
      Duration: 145 minutes; Preservation note: Audiotape transferred to new reel; Recording digitally stretched and reversed
    - Audiocassette, cuid43719 (Box 7, Audiocassette 66_114)
  - Goff, Irving; and Harold Smith. "Johnson was in command of the base, DeWitt Parker was commissar...", undated (Box 1, Reel 66_25, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_115, 66_116, Box 4, Cd 66_25)
  - Geiser, Carl., undated (Box 7, Audiocassette 66_110, 66_111)
  - Gittelson, Lester; Herman Klein; Max Robert Klonsky. Gittelson: "I was with the original GW Battalion, but... in July 1937, we became part of the ALB because... most of the men in the GWB and the ALB were either killed or wounded. I recall the day of the first major offensive vividly..." [Not transferable], undated (Box 1, Reel 66_26, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_120, 66_126)
  - Goff, Irving; Benjamin Goldstein. On Fuentes. [Not transferable], undated (Box 1, Reel 66_27, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_117, 66_118)
  - Groden, Daniel Samuel, undated (Box 1, Reel 66_28, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_119, 66_120, Box 4, Cd 66_28)
  - Harriman, Manny; and Allan Donald McNeil. "I had in my possession ...[documents that] were seized by the Eastern [?] Committee while I was in Pittsburgh during the infamous Jewish Cultural Center situation...", undated (Box 1, Reel 66_29, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_82)
  - Harriman, Manny; William Gilmore Wheeler. Harriman on MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion at Ebro; Wheeler on Jarama. [Not transferable], undated (Box 1, Reel 66_30, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_159, 66_160)
  - Kaufman, Rubin., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_31, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_96, Box 4, Cd 66_31)
  - Keller, Fred Paul., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_32, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_121, 66_122, 66_123, Box 4, Cd 66_32)
  - Keller, Fred Paul; Abraham Osheroff., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_33, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_103, 66_107, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_124, Box 4, Cd 66_33)
  - Klein, Herman. On first week in September, 1938, in the Sierra Caballs: "I was in the Third Company of the Lincoln-Washington under the command of Bill Wheeler...", Dec 1965 (Box 1, Reel 66_34, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_125, 66_129)
  - Klein, Herman; and Steve Nelson. [Not transferable], undated (Box 1, Reel 66_35, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_83, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_137, 66_138)
  - Klein, Herman; Charles Nusser; and Max Robert Klonsky. On Brunete; "...Martin Hourihan wounded in the April 5th attack? He was."; comments on the draft of Landis' book., Apr 3, 1965 (Box 1, Reel 66_36, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_128, Box 4, Cd 66_36)
  - Klein, Herman; Charles Nusser; Max Robert Klonsky; and Harold Smilth. Smith, commander of battalion headquarters company on the staff structure and events surrounding the loss of Lardner; Nusser or Klonsky on issues concerning the publication of Landis's book., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_37, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_127, Box 4, Cd 66_37)
  - Landis, Arthur; and Isadore Tivin. Landis demonstration tape, with instructions for veterans on how to make tapes; experience with MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion; Tivin on arrival at Albacete and training camp in Madrigueras., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_38, Box Shared Tamiment 168, Audiocassette 66_156, 66_157, Box 4, Cd 66_38)
  - Levine, Sidney; Donald MacLeod; Donald Thayer; and Wilbur Ed Wellman. Landis: "This tape is an excellent introduction"; MacLeod with transport, and covers a much wider field; Thayer on fighting in both towns as a lieutenant; Wellman on fighting with Lincolns at Quinto and taking of Hill 666; taking of Belchite., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_39, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_133, 66_134, Box 4, Cd 66_39)
  - Levine, Sidney; Donald Thayer. Primarily on Brunete Front., undated (Box 1, Reel 66_40, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_130, Box 4, Cd 66_40)
  - Love, Vaughn Costine; Steve Nelson; and Louis Secundy. Love on reasons why, as a black man, he volunteered for the SCW., Apr 3, 1965; cuid43084 (Box 2, Quarter inch audio reel 66_41, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_143, Box Shared Tamiment 168, Audiocassette 66_158, Box 4, Cd 66_41)
    Duration: 64 minutes.
  - MacLeod, Donald Transport unit called the 2nd Regiment de Tren on Brunete., undated (Box 2, Reel 66_42, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_131, 66_132, Box 5, Cd 66_42)
  - McNeil, Allan, undated (Box 7, Audiocassette 66_135)
  - Munday, Arthur; and Charles Nusser., Mar 7, 1965 (Box 2, Reel 66_43, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_136, Box 5, Cd 66_43)
  - Nelson, Steve. Nelson: "When the Madrid campaign was over, all the men... wanted to get back to Paris...", Jul 4, 1964 (Box 2, Reel 66_44, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_97, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_142, Box 5, Cd 66_44)
  - Nelson, Steve; and Charles Nusser. Nelson's response to criticisms of Landis about quality of earlier tapes: "I have perhaps as much information as any single American who was in the Brunete campaign... ", undated (Box 2, Reel 66_45, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_139, Box 5, Cd 66_45)
  - Nelson, Steve; Charles Nusser; and Harold Smith., Apr 1964 (Box 2, Reel 66_46, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_104, Box 5, Cd 66_46, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_140)
  - Nelson, Steve; and Al Warren. Nelson: "I arrived in Albacete somewhere around the middle of April in 1937. We came in from France by a little fishing boat... ran into an Italian destroyer on the way...", undated (Box 2, Reel 66_47, Box 6, Audiocassette 66_93, Box Shared Tamiment 168, Audiocassette 66_158, Box 5, Cd 66_47)
  - Parker, Max. From the First Transport Regiment, Prisoner, undated (Box 2, Reel 66_48, Box Shared Tamiment 168, Audiocassette 66_144, 66_145, Box 5, Cd 66_48)
  - Sennett, William [and Songs?]., undated (Box 2, Reel 66_49, Box Shared Tamiment 168, Audiocassette 66_148, 66_149, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_142, Box 5, Cd 66_49)
  - Smith, Harold. Equipment of Washington Battalion when they went into Brunete..., undated (Box 2, Reel 66_50, Box Shared Tamiment 168, Audiocassette 66_150, Box 5, Cd 66_50)
  - Stuart, Yale., undated (Box 2, Reel 66_51, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_132, Box Shared Tamiment 168, Audiocassette 66_152, 66_153, Box 5, Cd 66_51)
  - Taft, Anne (I). Side 2: "One day...a truck drove up and Dr. Bethune arrived with a refrigerator and blood for transfusions, and set up the transfusion service for us..." [Not transferable], undated (Box 2, Reel 66_52, Box Shared Tamiment 168, Audiocassette 66_155)
  - Taft, Anne (II)., undated (Box 2, Reel 66_53, Box Shared Tamiment 168, Audiocassette 66_154, Box 5, Cd 66_53)
  - Thayer, Donald. Current Medical Problems., undated (Box 2, Reel 66_54, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_126, Box 5, Cd 66_54)
  - Unknown Interviewee. Jarama., undated (Box 2, Reel 66_55, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_128, Box 5, Cd 66_55)
  - Zlotnick, Louis. From Chicago to New York to France, and Over the Mountain to Spain... [audiocassettes 66-129, 66-143], undated (Box 2, Reel 66_56, Box 7, Audiocassette 66_129, 66_143)
- Series II: Miscellaneous Reel-to-Reel Audiotapes, 1945-1970.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access copies for some recordings are available by appointment for reading room listening only. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives with collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
  - Unrelated to Landis Book Project: Moe Fishman, Steve Nelson, and Charles Nusser Discussion of African-Americans in VALB, [1967?] (Box 2, Item 66-57)
  - Unrelated to Landis Book Project: Moe Fishman --Discussing the registration of VALB as Communist Front Organization. [Damaged], undated (Box 2, Item 66- 58)
  - Unrelated to Landis Book Project: [Fritz Kreisler Music?] [audiocassettes 66-121, 66-122, 66-123], [Nov. 20, 1957?] (Box 2, Item 66- 59)
  - Unrelated to Landis Book Project: Landis: [History of the Spanish Civil War?] [audiocassettes 66-133?, 66-134?], undated (Box 2, Item 66- 60)
  - Unrelated to Landis Book Project: Landis: Reply to Moe Fishman, [1974?] (Box 2, Item 66- 61)
  - Unrelated to Landis Book Project: Landis: VALB Book, undated (Box 2, Item 66- 62)
  - Unrelated to Landis Book Project: Musicians Congress [audiocassettes 66-105, 66-106, 66-107], [June 15, 1965?] (Box 2, Item 66- 63)
  - Unrelated to Landis Book Project: Song Fest [Jane Collendar's House?], 1945 (Box 2, Item 66- 64)
  - Unrelated to Landis Book Project: Bart Van der Schelling, Sep 23, 1969; cuid43103 (Box 2, Audiocassette 66- 65, Box 5, Cd 66- 65)
    Duration: 66 minutes; Preservation note: 1/2 track captured in one pass. Track 2 had to be digitally reversed.
  - Unrelated to Landis Book Project: Bart Van der Schelling, [June 1969?]; cuid43104 (Box 2, Audiocassette 66- 66, Box 5, Cd 66- 66)